eseth.net 2015-02-14

# Privacy Policy - eSeth

eSeth.net has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy.  Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by [email](mailto:admin@eseth.net?subject=Contact)

**What Information do we collect?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, use our android app software, subscribe to our newsletter or fill out a form.

When you enter this website, we collect your browser information (which typically includes browser type, version, host operating system and browser language) and IP address. This information is gathered for all visitors. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information. When you complete a form on our website, we may ask you for your name, e-mail address, postal address and your telephone number's. This is so we can contact you easily if required.

Our site uses cookies. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. eSeth.net uses cookies to track user traffic patterns, to administer the display of advertising banners, and the discussion forum uses cookies to store the following information: the last time you visited the forums, your username, and a unique session ID number when you login. These cookies are stored on your browser.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys.

**Use of Information?**

The information you provide to eSeth.net will be used for the following reasons:

\- To ensure that content from our site is presented to you in the most effective manner.

\- To enable us to continuously enhance eSeth.net services, to serve advertising, and to provide to you information, products or services which we feel may be of interest to you.

\- To occasionally carry out market research including internal analytical research which will enable us to constantly improve your experience on eSeth.net.

\- To notify you about changes to or other information about our service.

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 

eSeth.net creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

**Sharing of Information**

eSeth.net uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. eSeth.net does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission.

**Opt-Out Policy**

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:   
\- Opting not to subscribe to receive our electronic newsletters.   
\- Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas (forums), which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users.

**External Links**

This site contains links to other sites. www.eseth.net is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**Google and the[ DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx)**[](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx)

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on eSeth.net.

Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to eSeth.net users based on their visit to eSeth.net.

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

**Google Analytics Tracking**[](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx)

eSeth has changed its Analytics tracking code on its website and android software applications to support Display Advertising. The features we have implemented is the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. You can choose to opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

eSeth will not facilitate the merging of personally-identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information previously collected from Display Advertising features that is based on the DoubleClick cookie.

Users can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

eSeth may use data from Google’s Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics. This helps eSeth better understand how our Service is being used and to help tailor content and advertising on the Service.

**Changes to Privacy policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently.

**Additional Information**

Kindly read [Terms of Service (TOS)](http://eseth.net/terms-of-service)

(Dated 24th March, 2014)
